Inside Sherman Klump, a party animal is about to break out.
The Nutty Professor is a fantasy, comedy, romance film directed by Tom Shadyac.
When beautiful Carla Purty joins the university faculty, genetic professor Dr.
Sherman Klump grows desperate to whittle his 400-pound
frame down to size and win her heart.
So, with one swig of his experimental fat-reducing serum, Sherman becomes
'Buddy Love', a fast-talking, pumped-up, plumped down Don Juan.
Sherman Klump / Buddy Love / Lance Perkins / Papa Klump / Mama Klump /
Grandma Klump / Ernie Klump, played by Eddie Murphy.
Carla Purty, played by Jada Pinkett Smith.
Harlan Hartley, played by James Coburn.
Dean Richmond, played by Larry Miller.
Reggie Warrington, played by Dave Chappelle.
Jason, played by John Ales.
The Nutty Professor is a 1996 American comedy film
starring Eddie Murphy as the titular character.
It is a remake of the 1963 film of the same name, which starred Jerry Lewis.
The remake, directed by Tom Shadyac, co-stars Jada Pinkett, James
Coburn, Larry Miller, Dave Chappelle, and John Ales.
Filming began on May 8, 1995, and concluded on September 8, 1995.
The original music score was composed by David Newman.
Murphy portrays a university professor, Sherman Klump, a brainy
and kind-hearted obese man who weighs 400 pounds.
A research scientist, academic, and lecturer, Klump develops a miraculous, but experimental, weight-loss
pharmaceutical, and hoping to win the affection of the girl of his dreams, tests it upon himself.
Just like Julius Kelp from the original film, Klump's vigorous,
charismatic, but evil alter ego takes the name "Buddy Love".
Murphy plays a total of seven characters in the film,
including Sherman and most of Sherman's family.
Sherman's nephew is the only member of the family
not to be portrayed by Eddie Murphy.
The film was a box-office hit and received positive reviews, with critics
particularly praising the makeup and Murphy's performance.
It won Best Makeup at the 69th Academy Awards.
The film's success spawned a sequel, Nutty Professor
II: The Klumps, released in 2000.
The film explores themes of overweight, overweight man,
campus, family dinner, jekyll and hyde.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.